Kostadis Roussos: Hello.
David Mendenhall: Hello, friends.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello, adventurers.
David Mendenhall: Wade, you joining us?
Wade Brown: Friends and Wade.
David Mendenhall: Friends and Wade.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, maybe.
Wade Brown: Maybe.
Wade Brown: No, that's fair.
David Mendenhall: Like you're in a low-light situation.
David Mendenhall: Oh, there you go, Wade.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah.
Wade Brown: Now I'm just, there's Vaseline all over the lens.
Wade Brown: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see if I can get Gary.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Dave.
UNKNOWN: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, your peculiar take on adventuring gold.
Kostadis Roussos: What Vukradin didn't, rather.
Kostadis Roussos: Peculiar approach.
Kostadis Roussos: Booker did.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: You have to understand that the entire economy of the area hinges on adventurers.
David Mendenhall: It could prove problematic, indeed.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, has attracted the attention of a group of people.
David Mendenhall: Oh, really?
David Mendenhall: Oh, I like this development.
David Mendenhall: We'll have to see how that goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so there will be.
David Mendenhall: Others who believe in organic fair trade gold.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I would say others who believe that far.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a big world.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sure we could find some species that.
David Mendenhall: Find some other fellow hippie adventurers who believe in Vukradin's warped sense of morality.
David Mendenhall: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, thinking paladins.
David Mendenhall: Maybe.
David Mendenhall: I don't know.
David Mendenhall: I've seen plenty of paladins who just take the gold.
Kostadis Roussos: You've seen one paladin who just takes the gold.
David Mendenhall: I think I saw one paladin who like tried to become evil on purpose for like to gain extra power.
David Mendenhall: That was pretty awful in strong.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's the paladin?
David Mendenhall: Olivier's character.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, he wasn't a paladin then.
Kostadis Roussos: He was a rogue.
David Mendenhall: Oh, he was a rogue?
David Mendenhall: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: No, the paladin was in the drow adventure.
David Mendenhall: The paladin was back in the drow adventure.
David Mendenhall: God, how long ago?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, by Ard.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So I have to admit that this weekend I was doing a triathlon.
David Mendenhall: I saw that.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Escape from Alcatraz.
Kostadis Roussos: Escape from Alcatraz.
David Mendenhall: Second time.
David Mendenhall: Congratulations.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: And as a result, I did not have time to write a summary.
David Mendenhall: I did not have time to do a triathlon.
Kostadis Roussos: So.
David Mendenhall: Gary.
Kostadis Roussos: Hi.
Gary Young: One second.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And then today, I have a real job now, unlike my previous year where I was doing nothing.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And as a result, I didn't even have time to like.
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway, I did not have time this week, so I apologize.
Kostadis Roussos: Cool.
Kostadis Roussos: I have to do the boring conventional thing of trying to remember what happened.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Also, does it not generate an AI summary?
Kostadis Roussos: I think it does.
Kostadis Roussos: I thought it did.
Kostadis Roussos: Maybe it does.
Kostadis Roussos: So how's everybody's week?
Wade Brown: I'm in hell.
Gary Young: Well, India.
David Mendenhall: Well, so back from India.
David Mendenhall: Congratulations.
David Mendenhall: You made it back.
Gary Young: Sorry.
Gary Young: No, he was saying something more serious.
Kostadis Roussos: Why are you in hell?
Wade Brown: Oh, it's not serious.
Wade Brown: It's just everything I basically left Roku for is like in spades here.
Wade Brown: We're now on like four or five pre-meetings before I can even get hardware in my hands.
Kostadis Roussos: Can I just say something?
Kostadis Roussos: Dave earned that.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, God.
David Mendenhall: I never made you go to Firefox.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you do D-Dave, Dave?
David Mendenhall: No, once did I do that.
Kostadis Roussos: You didn't.
Kostadis Roussos: Dave did.
David Mendenhall: I did not.
Kostadis Roussos: Other people did.
Kostadis Roussos: You can savor this moment.
Kostadis Roussos: Savor it.
Kostadis Roussos: You are allowed to save.
Kostadis Roussos: Wade, thank you for sharing.
Wade Brown: I need to come up with every possible eventuality in what is essentially a task of kernel driver debug.
Wade Brown: Like, I don't know how to plan my next three months around I'm going to look for the bugs in the kernel drivers and I'm going to fix them.
Wade Brown: But they want that and I won't get hardware.
David Mendenhall: This is where ChatGPT can help you a lot.
Wade Brown: No, this is where I just quit.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay.
Wade Brown: I'm just a contractor.
Wade Brown: What are they going to do?
Wade Brown: Fire me?
David Mendenhall: If you'd be interested in being a virtual machinist at Roku, I had somebody quit today, and I have an opening.
Wade Brown: A virtual machinist.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Wade Brown: What is that?
David Mendenhall: I suspect.
David Mendenhall: Do you want to integrate Hermes into the OS?
Wade Brown: Probably not.
David Mendenhall: Well, go look up what it is, and then you can think about it.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: Hermes?
Kostadis Roussos: How about this?
Kostadis Roussos: You wouldn't have to attend meetings.
Wade Brown: What's the problem?
Wade Brown: I like doing work, but it's just all meetings, wall-to-wall meetings.
Wade Brown: And I can't do shit.
Wade Brown: And they're like, well, bill hours and do something.
Wade Brown: There's nothing to do.
Kostadis Roussos: So the problem is that if you want to get stuff done, and then there's a whole army of people whose job it is to measure that you're doing stuff.
Wade Brown: I know.
Wade Brown: Oh, dude, these meetings are insane.
Wade Brown: It's two engineers and eight managers.
Wade Brown: Like, it's not an exaggeration.
Wade Brown: It's me and the FPGA guy and eight PM types.
Wade Brown: It's fucking nuts.
David Mendenhall: I can promise you you will not have 8 p.m.
David Mendenhall: types.
David Mendenhall: Because I've had a long day.
David Mendenhall: Let's play against this.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, sorry.
Gary Young: I'm going to ask the project manager with building out the plan for the testing.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So I dumped the AI summary so that folks can remember what happened last week.
David Mendenhall: I remember what happened.
David Mendenhall: We cleared out that previous dungeon and avoided the obvious trap and left it for the dwarves who are now dead.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I got conked out by an ostra jelly, but our helpful cleric brought me back up.
Gary Young: And then for the reason there was a match like a dagger in our inventory.
Gary Young: It's great.
David Mendenhall: Kraden was very unhappy to see that when he looked today.
Wade Brown: Kraden can get his panties out of a bunch.
Wade Brown: Be more pragmatic.
David Mendenhall: He has definitely not learned pragmatism yet.
Wade Brown: He's too young.
Wade Brown: He's an idealist.
David Mendenhall: But you know, there's always the character arc.
David Mendenhall: We'll see.
Wade Brown: Oh, I like it.
Wade Brown: It gives me room to, you know, try to shepherd him out of his shitheaded teenage days.
David Mendenhall: Right.
David Mendenhall: Maybe you could roll for initiative.
Wade Brown: Are we going to?
Wade Brown: I swear I had the character sheet open.
Wade Brown: Where'd it go?
Gary Young: So, Dave, you updated the spreadsheet incorrectly.
David Mendenhall: I'm sorry.
David Mendenhall: What did I do?
Gary Young: You need the blood money item section, not just the blood money money.
David Mendenhall: That actually did occur to me.
Gary Young: Feel free to go ahead and is blood money column.
David Mendenhall: I also considered that.
David Mendenhall: I'm so glad that we are aligned on this objective, Drow.
Gary Young: All right, we're going to do is Blood Money.
David Mendenhall: All right, is Blood Money?
David Mendenhall: The Boolean.
Kostadis Roussos: I have to decide, you know, like, what is who is what is Valfide thinking here?
Kostadis Roussos: Probably, how come the Drow haven't conquered the Overworlders and slaughtered them all and made them slaves of the Underdark?
David Mendenhall: I did in the last week that these are the bizarre machinations of surface dwellers.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but at this point in time, I'm just thinking she's probably thinking that, you know, given how effect you were.
Gary Young: Just keep in mind that she's not actually evil.
Kostadis Roussos: But she's a drowser evil.
David Mendenhall: Or blood.
David Mendenhall: I love it.
David Mendenhall: Full-on variable.
David Mendenhall: Can we make like a T and F?
David Mendenhall: And I guess these, I guess he believes these genasi are F.
David Mendenhall: So we'll go with F on that one.
Wade Brown: Can we do like a highlighting in Excel or not Excel, whatever, you know, to put a red tint on anything that's got true in that column?
Gary Young: I'm sure we could write a little bit of a JavaScript.
Gary Young: We're going to have to have two summary columns, two sum columns.
Gary Young: I'll work on it.
Kostadis Roussos: You could.
David Mendenhall: Oh, God.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So clearly, I just want to say something.
David Mendenhall: I have to say, I'm having more fun already than I was at the end of Storm King's.
David Mendenhall: Things are going well.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, yeah, we're full of potential right now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you know, it was a different era.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let me go to the initiative.
David Mendenhall: Orcork Ork.
Kostadis Roussos: Did I roll initiative?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I have numbers.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorting.
Kostadis Roussos: No, that's the wrong sort.
David Mendenhall: It's upside-down sort.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Vukradin, you are up first.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Jesus.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, is it hold on?
David Mendenhall: Hold on, hold on.
David Mendenhall: What's going on?
David Mendenhall: Why are these?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: How do I pronounce your name?
Kostadis Roussos: Is it Vukradin, Vukradin, Vukradin?
David Mendenhall: I think Vukradin.
Wade Brown: Or V Dog.
Wade Brown: Just call him V Dog.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, does anybody?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me ask you a question.
Kostadis Roussos: Does anyone other than your mother and your stalwart fans call you Vukradin?
Kostadis Roussos: Doesn't anybody use like a nickname like Din or Krad or Vuk?
David Mendenhall: I'm a serious musician.
David Mendenhall: Did you use my name?
David Mendenhall: I don't know what you think is going on here.
David Mendenhall: Vukradin will be fine.
David Mendenhall: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Do your friends call you Kasadoporium?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Are they your friends?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: He answers, what friends?
David Mendenhall: Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: Are they your friends?
David Mendenhall: No.
Wade Brown: For what it's worth, we can barely see the orcs.
Wade Brown: We can see maybe like two of them.
Wade Brown: The rest are kind of up here in the fog of war or something.
David Mendenhall: I'm going first.
David Mendenhall: This is very bad for the party that I'm going first.
David Mendenhall: I would like to parlay with the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you actually walk up to them and say, I wish to party?
David Mendenhall: Sadly, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Well.
Wade Brown: Oh, that boy's going to get himself killed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the orcs kind of say the orcs are kind of like, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: He's a dumbass.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, what they really say is, he recognizes our rights to this territory and is offering himself in sacrifice.
David Mendenhall: Sacrifice?
David Mendenhall: No, I just wanted to talk.
David Mendenhall: What is going on?
David Mendenhall: Why are you guys here?
David Mendenhall: Like, did you need something?
David Mendenhall: Do you need help?
David Mendenhall: Like, are you looking for a place to stay?
David Mendenhall: Like, are you hungry?
Wade Brown: Well, hold on.
Wade Brown: Do you offer to fluff their pillows while you're at it?
David Mendenhall: I've never encountered orcs before.
David Mendenhall: I'm very confused.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, it's worse than that.
Kostadis Roussos: You have encountered orcs before, but they were in whatchamacallit Storm King's.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: They were in Neverwinter and they were civilized.
David Mendenhall: Oh, even better.
David Mendenhall: There you go.
David Mendenhall: And even doubly confusing.
David Mendenhall: You came and listened to my music.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Do you need me to play for you?
David Mendenhall: I don't have my piano with me, but I have a trumpet.
Gary Young: You said a trumpet?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, a trumpet.
Gary Young: He said some.
David Mendenhall: I also have a clarinet.
David Mendenhall: Would you prefer that?
David Mendenhall: Do you want the reeded instrument or just the brass?
Wade Brown: So I don't understand any of this.
Wade Brown: Right.
Wade Brown: He's speaking in orc.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see.
Wade Brown: Clarinet is more appropriate for them.
Kostadis Roussos: They speak common in orc.
David Mendenhall: Common.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So, all right.
Kostadis Roussos: So he moves over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
David Mendenhall: And whacks me.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Orc number one.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Orc number one kind of is like whack.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, if you're going to give us a bonus round, we're going to take advantage of it.
Kostadis Roussos: And he reaches with his great axe, and Effen misses, proving that God loves fools and sinners.
David Mendenhall: All right, you missed.
David Mendenhall: Great.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: The battle is joined then.
David Mendenhall: All right, Soma.
David Mendenhall: Don't be an idiot like me.
Wade Brown: You got lucky, kiddo.
David Mendenhall: I did.
Kostadis Roussos: This is where one of you remembers that there were orc tribes that were coming down from the north.
David Mendenhall: We were told this by the mayor of the town or something.
Kostadis Roussos: No, the innkeeper.
David Mendenhall: The innkeeper.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Wade Brown: All right.
Wade Brown: We're going to go ahead and cast Ice Knife on number three.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Let's see.
Wade Brown: Actually, how high up are they?
Wade Brown: This is an incline, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: 20 feet.
Wade Brown: Okay.
Wade Brown: So theoretically, if I thorn-whipped a guy down, would he end up on like prone and take damage on the way down?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I guess so.
Wade Brown: All right, then maybe that's what we do.
Wade Brown: We're just going to thorn whip number two and drag him down.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, what's the saving throw or is it a two-hit?
Wade Brown: That's me.
Wade Brown: Five points.
David Mendenhall: 22 hits.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade Brown: It's a hit.
Wade Brown: Falls down.
Wade Brown: Yeah, he gets dragged.
Wade Brown: Let's see.
Wade Brown: On a hit, the target takes 1d6 and then pull it 10 feet closer, which means he tumbles down the hill.
Wade Brown: I assume that knocks him prone or something crazy.
David Mendenhall: You should bring him another five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm assuming this was 20 feet down.
David Mendenhall: Oh, I see.
David Mendenhall: I see.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So does he take fall damage?
Wade Brown: At the very least, he should be prone or something.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's definitely prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, good.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm saying, I'm trying to decide if he takes fall damage because he was rolled down.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he take prone damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Does he take fall damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Takes 1d6 worth of fall damage.
Kostadis Roussos: How about that?
Kostadis Roussos: That's a cost.
Kostadis Roussos: That's good enough.
Kostadis Roussos: That works.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Doesn't take the full 2d6.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I was trying to decide.
Wade Brown: All right.
Wade Brown: He takes one more.
Kostadis Roussos: So, six points of damage?
Wade Brown: Six points on orc number two.
Wade Brown: The important thing is he is CC'd.
Wade Brown: Init bonus.
Wade Brown: Somebody already got him.
Wade Brown: Good.
Wade Brown: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
David Mendenhall: Orc four.
Kostadis Roussos: Or four.
Kostadis Roussos: Is that what I heard?
Wade Brown: We heard orc four.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Orc four.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm currently futzing with technology.
Kostadis Roussos: That is not a good thing for me to be doing.
Kostadis Roussos: I should be focused on playing and not on, you know, goofing off with technology.
Kostadis Roussos: Because we all know that technology is, in fact, the source of all problems in modern society.
Wade Brown: No, it's PMs.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, since we have none here anymore, I suppose we could say that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So you did that.
Kostadis Roussos: What does number four do?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So he can move.
Kostadis Roussos: So he does.
Kostadis Roussos: One.
Kostadis Roussos: One, two, three.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's like, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: And he will attack Kraden again.
Kostadis Roussos: Why?
Kostadis Roussos: Because he happens to be closest.
Wade Brown: I mean, he did rush up into the front.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he did.
Kostadis Roussos: So it's not my fault.
Kostadis Roussos: Except I forgot to roll to hit.
Kostadis Roussos: 18.
Kostadis Roussos: You take 12 points of damage, Vukradin.
David Mendenhall: I am unconscious.
Kostadis Roussos: You are unconscious.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: And let me do my death save.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
David Mendenhall: I failed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: I think it's me.
David Mendenhall: It's going to be a very painful lesson that I learned.
Wade Brown: Or maybe you won't learn anything.
Wade Brown: You'll just be dead.
David Mendenhall: I'll just be dead.
David Mendenhall: Even better.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: We'll go with heal the word, healing word, and then Sacred Flame.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: You got 11 on a healing word?
David Mendenhall: I didn't even know it could be that powerful.
David Mendenhall: I thought it was like a d4.
David Mendenhall: It's 2d4.
Gary Young: I believe I have some.
Wade Brown: It says 2d4 plus 3 in the.
Wade Brown: He double crit.
David Mendenhall: Wow, nice.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: So I have nine hit points.
David Mendenhall: Thank you.
Gary Young: And one point in Sacred Flame.
Gary Young: To whom?
Gary Young: We're going to go with.
Gary Young: Actually, that's a good question.
Gary Young: Hold on.
Gary Young: Prone condition.
Gary Young: Why is Brewberry injured?
Gary Young: Didn't we do a long rest?
David Mendenhall: Do long rest.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wade Brown: Go ahead and reset everything.
Gary Young: Well, at any rate, it doesn't matter who I'm doing it on, so it will be on
Gary Young: four.
Gary Young: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Are you raging?
Gary Young: It is Brewberry's turn next.
Gary Young: I am.
Wade Brown: Could we skip the prone guy?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I didn't get.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, the prone guy.
Wade Brown: He should have gone before the cleric.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well.
Gary Young: Orc 2?
Gary Young: Yes.
Gary Young: Oh, yeah, you're right.
Gary Young: Orc 2.
Wade Brown: I mean, his only action is stand up, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he can.
Kostadis Roussos: Prone condition, you can remove the prone condition by reducing your move rate by 15.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Vukradin would still be dead.
Kostadis Roussos: So move Brewberry.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll just do.
Kostadis Roussos: Can I just do the orc after Brewberry?
Kostadis Roussos: How about that?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let's go.
Gary Young: It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry, go.
Gary Young: Go smash.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: But he doesn't have to be that close.
Gary Young: He can be like here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Let's say.
Kostadis Roussos: And since he was knocked prone, you do have advantage on him.
Kostadis Roussos: So roll again.
Kostadis Roussos: You missed the 12 missed.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade Brown: D20 plus 5.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 points of damage.
Gary Young: On number 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Which would.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: By the way, did one of the orcs make a saving throw on Sacred Flame for one hit point?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, number four made us.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I didn't roll that.
Kostadis Roussos: Number four was the guy.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know why he was moved.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I'm assuming.
Kostadis Roussos: What was your sacred flame?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he made the saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: One hit point.
Kostadis Roussos: Made his hit point.
Gary Young: Alright.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Done.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, this orc?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: What does this orc do?
Kostadis Roussos: He just got whacked by Brewberry, so he charges at Brewberry.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, what does the Cleave action do?
Gary Young: Oh, that's a good question.
Gary Young: Cleave, once per turn, if I hit a creature with a melee attack, I can make another melee attack against the second creature within five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so do your second attack.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Presumably on number one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: That is a hit.
Gary Young: The second creature takes a Halberd's damage, but without ability modifier.
Gary Young: So not this.
Gary Young: It would be...
Gary Young: That would be a nine damage.
Wade Brown: It would just be nine, yeah.
Gary Young: Nine damage on one.
Wade Brown: On one?
Wade Brown: All right.
Gary Young: That's useful.
Gary Young: I should, like, actually do that.
Gary Young: Yes.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: So I believe you said that two was leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: He was advancing to you.
Gary Young: That's correct.
Gary Young: He's leaving a square that I threaten.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, fair.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, what happens in that case?
Gary Young: That means that I get the attack of opportunity, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, fair enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Fair enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah.
Gary Young: Or?
Gary Young: So that's 18 to hit.
Wade Brown: If you have at least a plus three, you can't not kill him.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: He dies.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Well done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and I forgot to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold up.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: What would Orc 3 did?
Kostadis Roussos: Everybody's now decided Virkudin is a loser who can't add much value.
Wade Brown: He is a bard.
David Mendenhall: Kill him again.
Gary Young: So did anyone notice that Valfine is Yo?
Gary Young: That's because.
David Mendenhall: I saw that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's because.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's the texture of the map, isn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's supposed to say canyon.
Kostadis Roussos: So when your character's over it, it kind of goes in the background.
Wade Brown: It's weird that that's on the top layer, anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: I put it on the top layer.
Kostadis Roussos: It means that I can put these symbols on where they are, and they will show regardless of whether you've discovered it or not.
Kostadis Roussos: Otherwise, if you put it in the other layers and you don't have lighting, you can't see it.
Kostadis Roussos: So they had this new foreground layer that lets me do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Since this is causing people.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I know, I know.
Kostadis Roussos: But, you know, it was like, I was kind of annoyed by it, and so you guys brought it up, and I said, okay, I'm not going to look weird by being annoyed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So he attacks with his great axe.
Gary Young: On Valfine?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Alright.
Gary Young: AC17.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh!
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: One away from a crit at least.
Kostadis Roussos: For eight points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll take it.
Kostadis Roussos: Down to two.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Bukhridin.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: He understands now that he's fighting for his life here.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he not want to sit there and write a sonnet first?
David Mendenhall: He wants to live.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: He does not have a death wish.
David Mendenhall: He is not.
Wade Brown: He's not late stage or not or sick.
David Mendenhall: Three damage on number one, and then we'll attack again.
David Mendenhall: And he misses the second attack.
David Mendenhall: That's a shame.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: That means he gets to hit back.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Number one kind of notices that you hit him, so he's like surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, you got.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, it's kind of like, and he hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he hit?
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: And he swings his great axe and knocks me out again.
David Mendenhall: Wow.
David Mendenhall: I am not designed for tanking.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: I think I'm learning my lesson on this one.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: Soma, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: You've learned a valuable lesson.
David Mendenhall: I am definitely learning things.
David Mendenhall: Why they wanted to fight me, I don't know.
David Mendenhall: They wanted to fight me.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: I made my death site.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Soma.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah.
Wade Brown: I don't know.
Wade Brown: We'll just thorn whip him again.
Wade Brown: He should die from that.
Wade Brown: Right.
Wade Brown: Actually, no, poison spray.
Wade Brown: That can do 1D12.
Kostadis Roussos: What's the range of that?
Wade Brown: 30 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so it's a target?
Wade Brown: Yeah, it's target at number one.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Number one dies.
Wade Brown: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Dies.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Orc number four.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's get rid of it.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's get.
Kostadis Roussos: No, we aren't.
Kostadis Roussos: Folks aren't doing their jobs.
Kostadis Roussos: Getting rid of the orc, so we're down two and four.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I got rid of it.
David Mendenhall: So that as well.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Gary Young: Four is still up.
Gary Young: Three and four up.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: A battle is not lost, they think to themselves.
Kostadis Roussos: It could kill Valfi and it becomes two on two.
Kostadis Roussos: So.
Gary Young: Yeah, that's not going to help.
Wade Brown: Ignore the damage dealers.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's not a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Valfien, you're up.
Gary Young: Let's see.
Kostadis Roussos: Disengage is a good strategy.
Gary Young: Nah.
Gary Young: I'm enjoying the pain here.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I was worried you were going to say.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: Let's see.
Gary Young: They both are at full hit points.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Then I'll just attack four.
Gary Young: And then we'll go with
Gary Young: just a regular mace attack.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry.
Gary Young: Brewberry will attack from here.
David Mendenhall: We'll have the Halberd.
David Mendenhall: That is neat.
Gary Young: You can just cleave again.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit for seven points of damage on number three.
Kostadis Roussos: I marked it.
Gary Young: And then Cleave.
Kostadis Roussos: That is how much damage?
Kostadis Roussos: It's like six.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: When you're raging, you also add the certain number of points to your damage, which I don't think it does by default.
Gary Young: Yeah, but I forgot to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: Again?
Gary Young: I mean, I guess I could rage right now.
Gary Young: This is my turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
David Mendenhall: Go ahead and do it.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
UNKNOWN: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I almost feel that if Vukradin goes down, you automatically rage.
Gary Young: Not my long friend.
Gary Young: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: When Vukridine goes down, I'll automatically rage.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right.
Kostadis Roussos: You're like.
Kostadis Roussos: I think you automatically rage because this is, you know, he's the musical genius of your life.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So the first attack was nine points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Because you got a plus, you got a plus two to fix that.
Kostadis Roussos: And the second attack is you eight points of damage.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: Range bonus damage.
Gary Young: What is my range bonus damage again?
Kostadis Roussos: It's plus two.
Kostadis Roussos: I looked it up last time.
Kostadis Roussos: If you go to the second, the 2024 DD rules under barbarian tables, it goes plus two.
Kostadis Roussos: It's your proficiency bonus until a particular level, and then it goes to plus three, but it does not reach the same max as your proficiency, so it doesn't go to plus five.
Speaker 7: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All righty.
Kostadis Roussos: Orc number six.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so orc three suddenly realizes: hmm, is he clever enough to figure this out?
David Mendenhall: No.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he is.
David Mendenhall: Targets.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, he doesn't advance.
Kostadis Roussos: He throws his javelin at Brewberry.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: And he hits and he starts, and he says awful things about Oathguardian barbarians and questions, the circumstances of their birth and all that sort of stuff.
Gary Young: I will shrug off five damage worth of it.
David Mendenhall: Wow.
David Mendenhall: That is impressive.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: Death save.
David Mendenhall: That's a pretty sad combat for me.
David Mendenhall: You're a bard.
David Mendenhall: Failed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So my.
David Mendenhall: I like how you guys stopped standing me up.
David Mendenhall: That's appropriate.
David Mendenhall: It's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: It's almost done.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: No.
David Mendenhall: Oh, now you're up.
Wade Brown: Yeah, yeah.
Wade Brown: We're going to take down Valfine in the Fracas, but I don't know how much longer we got.
Wade Brown: So we're going to ice knife the guy in the back, and it'll probably shard onto everyone.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
David Mendenhall: Do it.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: Oh, nope.
Wade Brown: I just completely whiffed.
Wade Brown: Excellent.
David Mendenhall: No, no, but does it like area damage, though, right?
Wade Brown: Let me check.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: On hits, hit or miss the shard then explodes.
Wade Brown: Each creature within five feet must exceed.
Wade Brown: Dex saving throw, take two d6.
Kostadis Roussos: Including Valfine.
David Mendenhall: Including Valfine.
Wade Brown: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: At two hit points.
David Mendenhall: Just make your deck save.
David Mendenhall: You'll be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, she won't.
Kostadis Roussos: They'd already rolled the cold damage.
Kostadis Roussos: It was seven.
Wade Brown: Oh, right, right.
Wade Brown: Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: I failed my deck save.
Kostadis Roussos: So you are knocked out.
Wade Brown: Yes, but so is, let's see.
Wade Brown: Orc number one to be dead unless he makes his save.
Wade Brown: Actually, they'd both be dead unless they make their saves.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so what's the saving throw?
Wade Brown: Dex 13.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, D20, 2d20.
Kostadis Roussos: One makes it.
Kostadis Roussos: Unless both might make it.
Wade Brown: It's a 13, right?
David Mendenhall: I like that.
David Mendenhall: The end result of your attack is that you killed your ally and did no further damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, they all made it.
David Mendenhall: Well, no.
Wade Brown: Well done.
Gary Young: So now I do a death save right now.
David Mendenhall: Yes, you do.
David Mendenhall: I'm sorry, Valfi.
UNKNOWN: Cook.
Gary Young: Okay, 16.
Gary Young: The tactical brilliance of this crew is.
Kostadis Roussos: We're not a well-well.
David Mendenhall: It's a bit better.
Wade Brown: We just met each other on the road, right?
David Mendenhall: Like we got the ogres quite effectively.
Kostadis Roussos: You take D6 plus 3 damage.
Kostadis Roussos: You take 5 points of damage, Brewberry, but that's half because you're raging, so you're down to two points.
Kostadis Roussos: You're down two points.
David Mendenhall: Down to 10.
Gary Young: Oh, I take half because I take half when you're down, bro.
Gary Young: Then I probably took zero from the last attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Gary Young: Well, so you're saying I take two now?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: All right.
David Mendenhall: Valfine, second death save.
Kostadis Roussos: No, Vukradin.
David Mendenhall: No, Valfin's up.
David Mendenhall: Fail.
David Mendenhall: Okay, you're plus minus.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Can you please save the party?
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: Sorry, man.
Wade Brown: I'm still new to this whole magic thing.
Gary Young: Brewberry.
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Brewberry.
Gary Young: Well, we can just attack both of them with Alvert again.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
David Mendenhall: That sounds like a good plan.
David Mendenhall: That's a hit.
Gary Young: All right.
Wade Brown: And that is seven and ten.
David Mendenhall: That can be two kills.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Gary Young: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's make sure.
Wade Brown: Seven and seven.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, right.
Kostadis Roussos: Seven and nine.
Wade Brown: No, it's nine and because you're forgetting your plus two.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: They only have seven and six hit points.
Gary Young: That's nine and nine, I think, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: It'd be nine and nine and nine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: They're all dead.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: I presume Brewberry has to decide whether he's going to kill Soba, but maybe he doesn't.
David Mendenhall: I assume Brewberry is going to help Bukrada and his musician friend, right?
Kostadis Roussos: I think so.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And Soma, are you going to help a Valfine?
Wade Brown: I mean, absolutely.
Wade Brown: I'm going to help them up.
Wade Brown: Kind of sheepishly.
Gary Young: So are we doing medicine checks?
Gary Young: Is that how this works here?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm assuming since the combat is over, you're able to stabilize everybody.
Gary Young: Oh, sure.
Gary Young: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, right?
David Mendenhall: Long rest, everybody.
David Mendenhall: Maybe we could go back in the Bruin and lick our wounds and talk about what the hell had just happened.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Wait, hold on.
Gary Young: Yeah, go ahead and do that.
Gary Young: And I'll hurt the bodies.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I'll head on over.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that sounds good.
Wade Brown: Come on, Bukritan.
Wade Brown: Let's get you back somewhere where you can perform.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade Brown: Tell tales of your brush with death.
Gary Young: He needs to enjoy the art.
David Mendenhall: The orcs slaughtered us.
David Mendenhall: Slaughtered us.
David Mendenhall: Yes, it was the orcs.
David Mendenhall: And the orcs slaughtered us.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So the orcs are okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So then, okay, so.
Gary Young: I assume there's nothing of value on the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I didn't say that.
Gary Young: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I just need to friggin find something.
Wade Brown: They're suspiciously dexterous.
Wade Brown: So, you know, maybe they got something there.
Kostadis Roussos: There you go.
Kostadis Roussos: They've got a broken hat decks, a javelin, and some hide armor.
Wade Brown: Armor.
Kostadis Roussos: Hide armor.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you know, you could pick up the battle axes and try to sell them for battle axes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade Brown: Are they blood money battle axes?
David Mendenhall: Definitely.
David Mendenhall: They're absolutely stolen.
Wade Brown: But you're not aware that this happened.
David Mendenhall: As soon as I see them hit the party inventory, I will be.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry could.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you know.
Wade Brown: Yeah, Brewberry is just a walking arsenal, right?
David Mendenhall: From a practical standpoint, it's not money that's going to be shared with Bukraden, so it's effectively the same as the black hand.
Kostadis Roussos: I see.
Kostadis Roussos: So Bukraden is optimizing for a poverty lifestyle.
David Mendenhall: No.
David Mendenhall: You know how much these sending stones are worth?
David Mendenhall: He's practically rich at this point.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know for a fact they weren't stolen?
David Mendenhall: I was given assurances that they were.
Kostadis Roussos: I see.
Kostadis Roussos: We've already become directional.
Kostadis Roussos: Plus, I thought you were going to use.
David Mendenhall: I obtained those in a fair, honorable way.
Kostadis Roussos: So we don't do provenance here.
David Mendenhall: There's only so much you can do.
David Mendenhall: Come on.
David Mendenhall: Which wizard created them?
David Mendenhall: How did he obtain the spell components for casting this sending spell?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
natasha: I have a meme I need to share for old people.
natasha: You can read it out loud.
David Mendenhall: Wade's not old.
David Mendenhall: I don't think he can hear it.
David Mendenhall: Aw.
natasha: Tell me what you're doing.
natasha: Give me the phone call.
Kostadis Roussos: Exercise for people over 60.
Kostadis Roussos: Begin by standing on a comfortable surface where you have plenty of room on each time.
Kostadis Roussos: With a five-pound potato bag in each hand, extend your arms straight out from your sides and hold them there as long as you can.
Kostadis Roussos: Try to reach a full minute, then relax.
Kostadis Roussos: Each day, you'll find that you can hold this position for just a bit longer.
Kostadis Roussos: After a couple of weeks, move up to 10-pound potato bags.
Kostadis Roussos: Then try a 50-pound potato bag.
Kostadis Roussos: And eventually, work your way up to where you can lift a hundred-pound potato bag in each hand and hold your arm straight out for more than a minute.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm at this level.
Kostadis Roussos: After you feel confident at this level, put a potato in each bag.
David Mendenhall: That's close.
Gary Young: This resonated.
Kostadis Roussos: Natasha said this resonated.
David Mendenhall: I heard.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
natasha: I didn't find this funny.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So you show up here again, and Dazlin and Norbis are like, ah, you're back.
Kostadis Roussos: You're back.
David Mendenhall: They didn't die trying to destroy the gem.
Wade Brown: They didn't have the fracas or anything.
David Mendenhall: Are you sure they're not dead?
Kostadis Roussos: Did they do that?
Kostadis Roussos: You told them where the gems.
David Mendenhall: They absolutely would have done that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just trying to see when they did that.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, you guys, I'm just thinking, like, you guys went over there.
Kostadis Roussos: They wouldn't have done it the same day when you came out.
Kostadis Roussos: They would have waked up in the morning.
Kostadis Roussos: You guys went out to the orcs.
Kostadis Roussos: The orcs attacked.
Kostadis Roussos: So they probably kind of hid here to see whether you're alive or dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Because, you know, what's the point of having a gem if the orcs are going to kill you?
Kostadis Roussos: They're trying to decide whether they need to run, you know, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: They see you all come back.
Kostadis Roussos: And Dazlin and Norbis say, Hmm, you're back.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we're going to camp for a while.
Kostadis Roussos: I see.
Kostadis Roussos: You're not here.
Kostadis Roussos: You're not here for the gem, right?
Gary Young: We're here to partake of your hospitality.
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, ah.
Kostadis Roussos: Dazlin turns to Norbis.
Kostadis Roussos: Norbus turns to Dazlin.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, let's go over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And there's a nice little fire pit over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And they say that they decide that it's an appropriate time to cook a pleasant meal.
David Mendenhall: Okay, that's not right.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Ken makes it all kind of worth it.
David Mendenhall: I play my flute a little bit for them.
Kostadis Roussos: And it sounds like Vokradin made a new poem.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Slaughtered us, slaughtered us.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, all right.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Vokradin, so the next day, this is the third performance.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Not my path.
Kostadis Roussos: Dazlin was unimpressed.
Kostadis Roussos: Norbist was pleased.
Wade Brown: Keep at it.
David Mendenhall: I'll take at it.
David Mendenhall: I'll take that.
Kostadis Roussos: But both of them were disappointed that you chose to play one of your own personal compositions instead of one of the more popular diddies of the area.
David Mendenhall: I'm sure they were.
David Mendenhall: I've heard that a lot.
David Mendenhall: I've gotten that a lot.
Kostadis Roussos: But, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you guys going to wait for them to go or are you just going to leave?
David Mendenhall: Oh, you mean we're.
David Mendenhall: We long rested, and then I think we can head out.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You're heading out.
Kostadis Roussos: Yay, you're heading out.
Kostadis Roussos: All righty.
Kostadis Roussos: Where is this?
Kostadis Roussos: Sword Coast.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You're at the door of an excavation.
Kostadis Roussos: Phandalin.
Gary Young: Back to Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Gary Young: I see.
Gary Young: So what's on the vlog?
Gary Young: What?
Gary Young: What's on our vote?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there's several quests.
David Mendenhall: There was another.
David Mendenhall: Well, we have to get our 50 GP reward for this.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: For this first, let's go get this.
David Mendenhall: Organic Fair Trade Gold.
UNKNOWN: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: What level are you guys?
David Mendenhall: One.
Wade Brown: One.
Kostadis Roussos: On your way back.
Kostadis Roussos: On your way back as you're heading towards Phandalin.
Kostadis Roussos: You hear an ogre whistling, whistling.
David Mendenhall: I should be able to recognize the song.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll your harmonize.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll your.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Another 10.
David Mendenhall: Not the best roles.
Gary Young: 23 perception.
Gary Young: I assume I know where this ogre is.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He is coming up.
Kostadis Roussos: You're going on.
Kostadis Roussos: It's like hilly terrain.
Kostadis Roussos: So if you could imagine, sort of in hell like this, he's on that side and he's coming up.
Kostadis Roussos: So you guys can either try to meet him over there or try to sneak around.
David Mendenhall: Maybe I should ask your opinion this time.
David Mendenhall: Is this a fellow musician?
Gary Young: Seems like he would be a slave.
Gary Young: I mean, that's normally what we would have done with ogres, and that's a broad sign.
Gary Young: At least he's one of these surfaces.
David Mendenhall: Should we free him then?
Gary Young: Free him?
Gary Young: I guess that's the way you do these things on the surface.
David Mendenhall: All right, let's free the slave.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Slave, you are free.
David Mendenhall: That was not the outcome I expected, but let's try to free him.
Kostadis Roussos: Slave, you are free.
Wade Brown: We don't even know if he's a slave.
Wade Brown: Who jumped to that conclusion?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: I now need to set up an encounter.
Kostadis Roussos: Give me a second.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, hey, here we go.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: There are any like.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So I do not have.
Kostadis Roussos: I do not have.
Kostadis Roussos: I will have to do it this way.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: There is a.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
David Mendenhall: Stupid.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: Good times.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So.
Kostadis Roussos: And.
Wade Brown: So does he have any like bonds?
Wade Brown: Do we see any signs that he's actually a slave?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: He's definitely not a slave.
Wade Brown: He's just a wandering ogre.
Gary Young: 11 insight on Do.
Gary Young: I think he's a surface ogre.
David Mendenhall: Surface ogre.
Gary Young: Is he a surface ogre or an underground ogre?
Wade Brown: He's on the surface.
Gary Young: He could have been.
Gary Young: You know, like when the demons in Vietnamese are bronze on, you know, like there's all kinds of people from the underdark that, you know, made it to the surface.
Kostadis Roussos: 11.
Kostadis Roussos: Is there such a thing as an underground ogre?
Kostadis Roussos: Ogres of the underdark?
Gary Young: There were plenty of them in the slave pits and in the.
Kostadis Roussos: To be quite honest, to be quite honest, since there isn't actually a difference between them, you can't tell.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: With that level of insight.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: My higher level of insight.
David Mendenhall: I guess I would shout out at this point: Ogre, are you a musician or a slave?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: That would confuse anybody just whistling in the afternoon.
Gary Young: I hope you whistled the same song back to him.
David Mendenhall: Well, I tried, but I only got a 10 on my performance, so it wasn't so good.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, apparently, ogres covet food and treasure, and they spitefully destroy art.
Wade Brown: But he was whistling.
Wade Brown: That's making art.
David Mendenhall: Oh, slave?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you called him the musician.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, musician, music?
Kostadis Roussos: No, me, Kelly.
Kostadis Roussos: How dare you?
David Mendenhall: Wait, he doesn't like music?
David Mendenhall: Oh, I'm definitely rolling for initiative, though.
David Mendenhall: What do you want?
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: What do you get for hating on music?
Wade Brown: Oh, this kid's going to get us all killed.
David Mendenhall: All the blood money you'll get from killing him.
Wade Brown: I don't need blood money.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: Nice roll, Valfina.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Wade Brown: You showed up.
Wade Brown: You're 21.
David Mendenhall: You did.
David Mendenhall: She did.
Gary Young: All right.
David Mendenhall: Night, we did very well on that one.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: Well, I will definitely attack.
David Mendenhall: Valfina, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, hold on.
Wade Brown: The white surface is all grassland or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, grassland.
Wade Brown: Plain with something like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Easy terrain.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, easy terrain.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the important thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Moving between levels costs you, makes it extra.
David Mendenhall: I don't plan on moving, so good to know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Like if you were to, going down costs you double movement, going up costs you double movement, and it's 10 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: So I assume that your guy is five feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, the battle is joined.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Deck save 13.
David Mendenhall: Alrighty.
David Mendenhall: Are we going to do 59 damage?
David Mendenhall: This is going to be a process.
David Mendenhall: That's going to be a process.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: He takes four points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: It's four damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Does Valfina stay within 30 feet, which is his movement rate, or does she take a few steps back to try to avoid being within his charge range?
Gary Young: Brewberry is going to be in front.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That's Valfina's new strategy.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Vokradin, you're up.
David Mendenhall: Starry Wisp.
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
David Mendenhall: What's the two hit on this ogre?
David Mendenhall: 11, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: That's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: What does that do?
Wade Brown: Damage.
David Mendenhall: Eight radio.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So eight points of damage.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, the range is 60 feet, so I can definitely head back over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Who is next?
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry.
Kostadis Roussos: Roar!
David Mendenhall: Charge!
David Mendenhall: Rage?
Kostadis Roussos: Don't forget to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember, he said he doesn't like music.
Gary Young: Yeah, that's right.
David Mendenhall: Unbelievable.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll to hit.
Gary Young: Of course, I can't cleave, but
Gary Young: no, no.
Gary Young: Plus two attack with the.
Kostadis Roussos: I only think it's for damage, though.
Gary Young: Is it only damage?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Gary Young: I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: They changed everything.
Gary Young: My abilities work.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I'm not expecting you.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm kind of like, this is like sort of like, I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: I have to go read the new player's handbook.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: It's dish damage.
Kostadis Roussos: It's not to hit.
Gary Young: Advantage on strength checks.
David Mendenhall: Ignore that.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay, just advantage on strength checks.
Gary Young: So a 10 is a myth, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: All right then.
Gary Young: But I'm not reaching.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Ogre.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the ogre marches up to you and says.
Kostadis Roussos: You left a square with my.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it is true.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: A crit.
Kostadis Roussos: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Plus four points of damage.
David Mendenhall: You ranged, though, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So that's 19 plus 4 because you double the.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He's down to 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Damn.
Kostadis Roussos: Halfway there.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: He's kind of like, damn.
David Mendenhall: That was impressive.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: The ogre is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, well done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: That's 10 points of damage, or 5 points of damage if you're raging.
Gary Young: I guess I'll take the five points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade Brown: Good call.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: All right.
Wade Brown: We'll come on up a little closer and just can't trip away.
Wade Brown: Let's go poison spray.
Wade Brown: That's a hit, right?
Wade Brown: He's 11?
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, that's a hit.
Wade Brown: Seven damage, taking him to 17.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: There's no poison condition related to poison spray, right?
Wade Brown: No, it's kind of weird.
Wade Brown: It just does 1d12 poison damage.
Wade Brown: That's it.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Valfina?
David Mendenhall: 112 is pretty nice.
Wade Brown: Yeah, it's a really nice cantrip.
David Mendenhall: It just does nothing.
David Mendenhall: I don't have anything that does 1d12.
David Mendenhall: That's awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you know.
David Mendenhall: Deck save DC13.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Ogres have really bad dexterity, so that is a good choice.
Gary Young: It's all I can have options.
Gary Young: Oh, that's a crit on natural 20.
Gary Young: Sorry.
David Mendenhall: What's he down to?
David Mendenhall: 17.
David Mendenhall: 17 on the end of my turn.
Gary Young: Vokradin.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming she stepped over here and then stepped over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Vokradin, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: What did you just hit with?
Kostadis Roussos: Starry Wisp?
Kostadis Roussos: With Stranger?
David Mendenhall: Three radio.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You did that.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Only three?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that's not a great damage roll.
Kostadis Roussos: Is that another miss?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's another miss.
Kostadis Roussos: You literally had a 25% chance to miss.
Kostadis Roussos: It's not that rare.
David Mendenhall: Did somebody record the three damage?
Kostadis Roussos: No, could you please do that?
Wade Brown: Oh, yeah, he's at 14 now.
David Mendenhall: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Brewberry is done.
Kostadis Roussos: Ogre is done.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, the ogre is up.
Kostadis Roussos: Ogre does nine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, what does Brewberry's animal class?
Kostadis Roussos: No, misses.
David Mendenhall: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: All right, Soma.
Wade Brown: All right.
Wade Brown: Hypothetically, I could thorn whip him away from you.
Wade Brown: Would you get an opportunity attack of opportunity?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you would.
Wade Brown: All right, let's do that.
Wade Brown: I'm going to come over here and just try to yank him away so you can get a free hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade Brown: It looks like that's pretty good.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So what does that do?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you missed again.
Wade Brown: He takes 1d6 and I pull him 10 feet closer.
Wade Brown: So I do have to pull him out of the way.
Wade Brown: So move him like, just move him one square over.
Kostadis Roussos: 5, 10.
Kostadis Roussos: That's 5 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: That's 10 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: He's right next to you.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's also not prone, right?
Wade Brown: It doesn't say anything about prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Then he's only fine.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I was just trying to give me the attack.
Wade Brown: Oh, well.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: We did record six damage, so there's another.
Wade Brown: He's at eight.
Gary Young: Yep.
Gary Young: Valfina, you're up.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: Sacred Flame might work this time.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Again, a good choice.
Kostadis Roussos: This time it does work, and he takes five points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Did someone apply it?
Wade Brown: No, no, he should be at three now.
Kostadis Roussos: He's at three.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Soma, you're up.
Wade Brown: I just.
Wade Brown: Yeah.
Wade Brown: Someone's at the bottom.
David Mendenhall: I'm going to move my token a little bit.
David Mendenhall: And then.
Kostadis Roussos: No, wait, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewberry just went, right?
Wade Brown: No.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Valfina.
Wade Brown: Valfina just went.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Soma just went.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, sorry.
Wade Brown: Yeah, I did the thorn whip.
Wade Brown: Brewberry missed his octoportity.
Wade Brown: Valfina did sacred flame.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, I got it.
Kostadis Roussos: I just got my guy.
Wade Brown: That's death if he dies if he takes the whole damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he dies.
David Mendenhall: He's dead.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Die, you anti-musician slave.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see.
Kostadis Roussos: What this treasure does he have?
Wade Brown: I had no idea you were so easily triggered.
David Mendenhall: I had to fight orcs, to fight an ogre, ochre jellies.
David Mendenhall: Not what I signed up for.
Gary Young: What did you sign up for?
David Mendenhall: Well, we were just supposed to go tell the dwarves that there was a dragon in the area and then go back to town.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You find walloping and ammunition on him.
Wade Brown: What?
David Mendenhall: No doubt stolen from another adventurer.
Kostadis Roussos: A creature hit by this ammunition must succeed in a DC saving throw or have the prone condition.
Gary Young: Who has ranged weapons?
David Mendenhall: Not it.
David Mendenhall: Not me.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Well.
David Mendenhall: You can always sell it.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You find the walloping ammunition in a fortunately for you, the ogre did not know how to use it.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fortunate.
Kostadis Roussos: Possibly because the ogre prefers just walloping people.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, the ogre is modus vivendi.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So you arrive in Phandalin.
Gary Young: So is there a reason that Valfina does not have a handed crossbow?
Gary Young: I mean, she's a drow.
Kostadis Roussos: No, she could have a hand crossbow.
David Mendenhall: You could buy one.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I almost feel like a draw without a hand crossbow is kind of like not a real drow.
Gary Young: Yeah, seriously.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: It's sort of like less in the drow.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You arrive in the town master's hall.
David Mendenhall: It is time to collect our reward.
Wade Brown: Our justly earned gold pieces.
David Mendenhall: Honorably earned.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you show up at the
Kostadis Roussos: do something.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So we arrive at the townmaster's hall.
Kostadis Roussos: To your you knock on the door, the door is again closed shut.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you knock on the door?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I want my money.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, if you're your voice again going, if you're a dragon, know that I'm far too thin and body to make a good meal.
Wade Brown: Dragons aren't usually the type to knock.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Wade Brown: Sometimes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, you do remember that asking him about a quest, talking to him about a quest gets him to walk out of his room.
Kostadis Roussos: So you ask him about the last time you asked him about a quest, he stopped, like he's not responding to you.
Kostadis Roussos: You could be a trick.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know for a fact that you're not the dragon.
Kostadis Roussos: So just go away.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm too skinny.
David Mendenhall: I'm sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: I got a 20 persuasion.
David Mendenhall: I should be able to persuade him out the door.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh!
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I think I've heard your voice before.
Kostadis Roussos: You're that bard that played in the Stonehill Inn.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, that's me.
David Mendenhall: You're a sister.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: But I do recall.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Should I remember you?
UNKNOWN: Disappointment.
David Mendenhall: Well, anyway, we came here for our money.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you came here for your money.
David Mendenhall: So did you tell the dwarves about the dragon?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you told.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, excellent, excellent, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm feeling much happier.
Kostadis Roussos: They're very charming people, you know.
David Mendenhall: They seem kind of like grave robbers.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: You don't think?
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses and goes, What do you mean they think they're grave robbers?
David Mendenhall: Well, I mean, they were, you know, digging in a ruin for artifacts, and I don't think they were intended to put all those artifacts in a museum.
Kostadis Roussos: Harbin goes.
Kostadis Roussos: His lordship, never remember, said that adventurers are allowed to seize and control whatever treasure they wish.
David Mendenhall: Well, that doesn't seem right at all.
David Mendenhall: Anyway, I will go with my typical diatribe.
Kostadis Roussos: Harbin has this look.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to roll your insight?
Kostadis Roussos: Does anybody want to check their insight or investigation?
Kostadis Roussos: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Valfina picks up that he is very unhappy.
Kostadis Roussos: With?
Kostadis Roussos: With Vukraden's behavior.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukraden's morality.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Did he pay me my 50 gold pieces?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he did.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: Well, that's all I really care about.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He is very upset with what he's heard.
David Mendenhall: You're upset with the orcs attacking the fine, upstanding, moral citizen, a Faerûn?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, do you ask him about it?
David Mendenhall: No, I'm just surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, well, I'm just telling you.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just saying he seems very upset, anxious even.
David Mendenhall: Interesting.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So there are the next set of quests.
Kostadis Roussos: Harvin says, well, since you seem to be in the business of being a hero and don't want to take any more treasure, the good news is that I have plenty more quests for you.
Gary Young: Awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: We seem to be having a shortage of adventures these days.
Kostadis Roussos: Something about the dragon terrorizing everyone.
Gary Young: How about something other than dragon?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I suppose I could get you something other than a dragon.
Kostadis Roussos: We always have.
Kostadis Roussos: He turns to you.
Kostadis Roussos: You won't have any real issue with the.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, he goes, all right, okay, what's okay, so there's okay, there's two more quests.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see whether I can have, let me see, they actually provided this.
David Mendenhall: Rock gnomes and the midwife.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, they don't have the quests.
David Mendenhall: I only have it copied nicely into the spinning.
David Mendenhall: Which one paid better?
David Mendenhall: I think it was the gnomes paid better, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: How about gnomes?
Wade Brown: Ever the starving artist.
Kostadis Roussos: And then we're going to show our organic fair trade gold.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: We sell them in the shop and sell our blood money to the Lionshield Coster.
Gary Young: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: What about the sending stones?
David Mendenhall: Should we keep those or sell them off?
Kostadis Roussos: You're not going to have anybody to sell them off in this town.
David Mendenhall: Oh, interesting.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Well, I guess we're keeping them then.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: In terms of the weapons, you can sell them to the Smithy.
Kostadis Roussos: He'll be happy.
Kostadis Roussos: He'll be happy for half price.
Gary Young: For half price.
Kostadis Roussos: They're damaged.
Gary Young: Half price, not 90% price?
Kostadis Roussos: No, half price.
Kostadis Roussos: They're damaged.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: So.
Kostadis Roussos: They were damaged.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if I didn't say that, that's my bad.
Wade Brown: I feel like you did.
Kostadis Roussos: I think I did.
Gary Young: Okay, it's fine.
Gary Young: And same with the hide armor?
Kostadis Roussos: The hide armor is in fine shape.
Kostadis Roussos: You can sell that to Lionshield Coster for scale for what is not with the thing that's just one step above the leather armor.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: It's normally worth 10 gold, so.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you can sell it for 10 gold.
David Mendenhall: For 9, I assume, because we have a jewel back there and the gemstones.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, who do you sold those to?
Kostadis Roussos: Barthen's Provisions?
Kostadis Roussos: Tell us.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Gary Young: The jewel backer might go to the blacksmith.
Gary Young: You might find that interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm trying to see something.
Kostadis Roussos: Where is Phandalin?
Kostadis Roussos: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I was looking for.
Wade Brown: I'll be back in a moment.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so.
Kostadis Roussos: Fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So you go to the.
Kostadis Roussos: So while you're going to the various stores, to the Smithy, to Lionshield Coster, when you get to the Lionshield Coster store,
Kostadis Roussos: Linene.
Kostadis Roussos: She says, oh, you're still alive.
Gary Young: This time.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes?
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
David Mendenhall: I had several near-death experiences.
David Mendenhall: It's a new thing for me.
David Mendenhall: I've never had this happen before.
Gary Young: The pain was glorious.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you awkward.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, well, as you know, ever since the Lionshield Coster used to have a big business, unfortunately, there were things that happened that have made our business not as able to provide all the goods that people would like, but we're still in business.
Gary Young: What has disrupted your trade?
Kostadis Roussos: You know, that's sort of an in-business.
Kostadis Roussos: Supply chains, it's all very technical.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Gary Young: Tariffs.
David Mendenhall: Tariffs.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, tariffs, sir.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right.
Gary Young: Reservable tariffs.
Gary Young: Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Tariffs, some disruptions, market force dynamics.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Need any help with that?
David Mendenhall: She looks at you and says, well, you have a shipment that you need us to go procure for you or poorly or can we offer our services?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
David Mendenhall: It would be a fair and honorable way for us to earn money.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's what you meant.
Kostadis Roussos: I thought you meant to actually solve my problem of the.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, ah.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but not today.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm not expecting a shipment.
David Mendenhall: Was there another problem you needed help with?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, actually, not really, but I did hear a rumor.
Gary Young: What's the rumor?
Kostadis Roussos: Strange magic pervades Neverwinter Wood, confounding navigators and obscuring the ancient ruins of bygone kingdoms lost in its depths.
Kostadis Roussos: Here, I'll cut and paste it.
Kostadis Roussos: I cut and pasted into the chat.
Kostadis Roussos: I put it in the off tracker.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: And so she says, will you be staying at the Stonehill Inn?
Gary Young: Yeah, I suppose so.
Gary Young: I mean, what time is it?
David Mendenhall: I guess we do have the money for that now.
David Mendenhall: That's a new treat yourself.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, yeah, you know, it's like the Stonehill Inn is going to be open for business.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Time.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: You arrive at the Stonehill Inn, and Toblen, the Stonehill Inn Tavern Keeper, Toblen Stonehill is very happy to see you.
Kostadis Roussos: And he says, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
Kostadis Roussos: It's so wonderful to see you.
Gary Young: Yes, wonderful to see you too.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Beer.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Did you say beer?
Gary Young: Wonderful to see you too.
Gary Young: Beer?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, beer.
Gary Young: Beer.
Gary Young: Song.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, well, I can't do song, but if I recall correctly, your friend here does an excellent song.
David Mendenhall: You have a piano?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I still haven't bought a piano.
David Mendenhall: So flute or clarinet, then?
Kostadis Roussos: Are you asking if I have any of those interests or something?
David Mendenhall: No, no, no, I have one.
David Mendenhall: Well, which would you prefer?
David Mendenhall: I'm happy to play.
Kostadis Roussos: Flute or clarinet.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, whichever one you prefer.
Kostadis Roussos: Clarinet.
David Mendenhall: Thank you, thank you.
David Mendenhall: I assume you want one of your pop numbers.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: If I recall correctly, you were doing something that you did that was very, very good.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: An average performance.
Kostadis Roussos: Good music.
Wade Brown: This is your plus five never hitting above like 20.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I don't know.
David Mendenhall: I've been rolling badly tonight.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Where's my 25 performance?
David Mendenhall: I want that.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So he goes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That won't work.
Kostadis Roussos: So, all right, so there's a few more people in the town, in the inn.
Kostadis Roussos: You can ask if they have any more, if they've heard any more rumors, or you can go spend the night sleeping.
David Mendenhall: Go ahead, guys.
David Mendenhall: I'm just playing the flute.
Gary Young: I guess Chalca will check the mood of the crowd.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: Because, you know, everyone loves a drill asking questions.
Wade Brown: I think suss about that.
David Mendenhall: Totally normal.
David Mendenhall: Completely fair.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Be fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So roll your perception or investigation.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll your insider investigation.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: Insight.
David Mendenhall: Now you're plus five ain't it average.
Gary Young: So with all my attack rolls with plus five and then this one with plus five.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Quite honestly, you know, you can't really tell.
David Mendenhall: Selma, you want to take a take a try?
David Mendenhall: Oh, shoot.
David Mendenhall: How about Brubery?
Gary Young: No, he's listening to the music.
David Mendenhall: I mean, I have a minus one.
David Mendenhall: Of course he is.
David Mendenhall: There you go.
David Mendenhall: Oh, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Lovely.
David Mendenhall: Jesus Christ, guys.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: So we just have our existing quests.
Gary Young: I guess that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: So you're not going to ask anybody?
David Mendenhall: No, we did.
Gary Young: We did.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I thought he was doing an investigation to see if anybody was.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, good grief.
Kostadis Roussos: Did I miss something really funny?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: I was trying to come up with rumors and frantically going through my DMG guide.
Gary Young: No, you don't need to bother with that.
David Mendenhall: We didn't roll well enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Don't worry.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So next morning, and off to Gnomengarde.
David Mendenhall: What did that cost?
David Mendenhall: It's a gold.
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't actually see that.
David Mendenhall: I assume the town's not the inn's not free, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I just realized that.
David Mendenhall: One gold.
David Mendenhall: That's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: One gold.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, let's just make it one gold.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So off to Gnomengarde.
Kostadis Roussos: Where is this?
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, I hadn't put you on the right map.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, here we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Gnomengarde.
Kostadis Roussos: So you go through.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to go through the hilly terrain, go to the grasslands, or just head?
Kostadis Roussos: Like, how do you want to go?
Wade Brown: Which direction is it?
Wade Brown: Oh, that's the form of an activation.
Wade Brown: No, wait, that's where I came here.
Gary Young: Hold on, sorry, sorry.
Gary Young: I just realized.
David Mendenhall: Where is it?
Gary Young: Valfina would like to go through the most brightly lit path possible.
David Mendenhall: Most paths.
David Mendenhall: Just go straight.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Through the hilly terrain.
Kostadis Roussos: Through the forest.
Gary Young: Pesky tree cover.
Gary Young: I need to have this sun.
David Mendenhall: 10 miles.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, no, it's 15.
Kostadis Roussos: It's 15 miles.
Gary Young: I thought you were allergic to the sun.
Gary Young: No, no, the sun is gloriously painful.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you're not really understanding the whole Valfina thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: What do we have to do with the gnomes?
David Mendenhall: Let me remind me.
David Mendenhall: How quickly can we get this done?
David Mendenhall: Gnomes are known for their magical inventions.
David Mendenhall: They might have something to do with the Key of the Dragon.
David Mendenhall: Get whatever you can from them.
David Mendenhall: So just we just need to trade with the gnomes.
David Mendenhall: Okay, that's fast.
David Mendenhall: We can trade very quickly.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Wade Brown: Holding on.
David Mendenhall: Holding on.
David Mendenhall: We can get whatever we can.
David Mendenhall: We might be able to get nothing.
David Mendenhall: And then we've gotten whatever we can, and we get our 50 gold pieces.
Wade Brown: Technically correct.
Wade Brown: The best kind of correct.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on here one second.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, so let's do that this way.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Vacuous troop.
Kostadis Roussos: So as you're going through
Kostadis Roussos: Valfina, so imagine this is a, you're going through the mountains, right?
Kostadis Roussos: As you turn around the corner, so imagine this is a mountain pass kind of thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Hey, ogre is standing in the middle of the way.
David Mendenhall: Another ogre.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Valfina, is this one a slave too?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me check.
Wade Brown: Is it whistling?
Gary Young: 14.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's definitely not a slave.
Gary Young: Because usually when they're slaves, they don't whistle cheerfully.
David Mendenhall: So he just wants to kill us then, like the other one.
David Mendenhall: Like everybody out here just wants to kill us.
Kostadis Roussos: The ogre goes,
Kostadis Roussos: I'm hungry.
Kostadis Roussos: I want you.
David Mendenhall: We have food.
David Mendenhall: Can we just give you some food and you can stand over there?
David Mendenhall: Because we're just walking past you.
David Mendenhall: Can we do that?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks.
Kostadis Roussos: I like turtle.
Wade Brown: Excuse me.
David Mendenhall: I don't have any rations?
Kostadis Roussos: Turtle.
Kostadis Roussos: I eat turtle.
Wade Brown: No, no, eat turtle.
Kostadis Roussos: Do we have something else to feed him?
David Mendenhall: Anybody?
Kostadis Roussos: So you're going to have to try.
Kostadis Roussos: If you want to persuade him, you're going to have to intimidate him.
Wade Brown: Intimidate an ogre?
David Mendenhall: I could try that.
David Mendenhall: That's not happening.
David Mendenhall: It's not usually my style, but let's see what happens.
David Mendenhall: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: You do not succeed in intimidating.
David Mendenhall: Do you guys want to try intimidation?
Kostadis Roussos: Go for it.
David Mendenhall: Valfina, you got to roll.
David Mendenhall: See if you can get under us.
Kostadis Roussos: Did I?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: You got to try it.
David Mendenhall: Excellent.
David Mendenhall: Well done, guys.
David Mendenhall: Well done.
Wade Brown: I told you, you don't intimidate ogres.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think the ogre.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think the ogre was intimidated.
David Mendenhall: We know.
Kostadis Roussos: In fact, I think the ogre now is excited because he saw your attempted intimidation and thinks this is going to be an easy.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I eat turtle elf.
David Mendenhall: I've killed other ogres like you.
Wade Brown: Just yesterday, we took out one of your brothers.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, did you say that?
David Mendenhall: We should get a plus two.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I would say that.
David Mendenhall: I'm getting kind of ticked off now.
Wade Brown: Let's kill me.
Wade Brown: Yeah, let Vukraden say it.
David Mendenhall: All I ever wanted to do was play music.
Kostadis Roussos: You killed my brother.
David Mendenhall: I think it actually enrages him further.
David Mendenhall: I love it.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a free rage.
Kostadis Roussos: It enrages him.
Wade Brown: It's going, kiddo.
Wade Brown: You just ticked him off.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let me just put an ogre in the combat tracker.
Wade Brown: Another one.
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, it's you know, it's like what you encounter on the module.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: No, it's fine.
David Mendenhall: It's fine.
David Mendenhall: Well, I'm going to have to stop, I think.
Kostadis Roussos: Should we stop at the end of this?
David Mendenhall: I'm going to try some different spells.
David Mendenhall: Got some other ideas.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Brubery.
Kostadis Roussos: Valfina and Brubery, you need to put your machine rolls.
Gary Young: 11 and 9.
UNKNOWN: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Selma, you're up.
Wade Brown: Oh, man.
Wade Brown: I'm burst.
Wade Brown: How did that happen?
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So just to give you an idea, right?
Kostadis Roussos: You're in the middle of a sort of a valley with a...
Wade Brown: Yeah, no, I was wondering if I could just mold earths and rocks on top of them or something.
Wade Brown: I mean, he's literally surrounded by.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just trying to think.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm actually saying yes, but I just don't know how to measure the damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah, it's...
Wade Brown: Does this actually have a roll?
Wade Brown: What happens when I roll?
Wade Brown: Oh, it just does that.
Gary Young: You can just roll can't trip damage if you want to make it easy.
Wade Brown: Well, you know, I like the idea.
David Mendenhall: I mean, it would be like the dirt that's above him.
David Mendenhall: You would loosen it, and then it would fall on him.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, especially from quite high up.
Wade Brown: Could make a good rock slide or something onto him.
Wade Brown: You know, like
Wade Brown: we make a big old, basically like a rock avalanche come down on him or something.
David Mendenhall: It says this movement doesn't have enough force to cause damage.
Wade Brown: Well, yeah, but from up above, it's taking all that potential, that potential energy gets converted into damage.
Wade Brown: Like dropping a penny off the Empire State building.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah.
David Mendenhall: Can that kill you?
Wade Brown: I don't think it can, but that's just because pennies have a very low terminal velocity.
David Mendenhall: And no.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So I will declare that it would cause 16 worth of damage.
Wade Brown: All right, we'll just poison spray him.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Screw being creative.
Wade Brown: Good old poison spray.
Wade Brown: Nothing beats that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, yeah, unfortunately, the mold earth spell.
Kostadis Roussos: The problem is.
Wade Brown: That's fine.
Wade Brown: It's not meant for damage.
Wade Brown: I just kind of wanted to screw around.
Wade Brown: So I'll just do it.
Kostadis Roussos: But you could, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You could have used it to make the terrain difficult so he can't charge at you.
Wade Brown: Yeah, but that also makes it hard for Brubery to get in there.
David Mendenhall: I have other ideas on that.
David Mendenhall: All right, eight damage.
Wade Brown: Yeah, 51.
Wade Brown: And I'm actually going to scoot back since he said turtle was sort of his favorite food.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Unfortunately, he made it.
David Mendenhall: Put me in front.
David Mendenhall: Thanks, dude.
Wade Brown: You're the one who pissed him off.
Wade Brown: Poison Spray doesn't have a saving throw.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, it's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, it's his hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, my bad.
Wade Brown: Yeah, he just takes eight damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
Wade Brown: No question.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: Ogre's up.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Ogre's like.
Wade Brown: Alrighty.
David Mendenhall: Hey, taste, bad.
David Mendenhall: Don't come after me.
Kostadis Roussos: No, hold on.
Gary Young: Our turn order leaves something to be desired.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, our marching order was not marching order.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think that would be.
Kostadis Roussos: He would be here.
David Mendenhall: I think I would be in the back.
David Mendenhall: I'm going to get in the back.
David Mendenhall: I don't think that looks more sane.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I can't imagine that would have been your order.
Gary Young: Oh, he exited a square that I'm threatening.
David Mendenhall: No.
David Mendenhall: That's right.
David Mendenhall: Ogre is up first.
Gary Young: Yeah, but I still get my reaction on him.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you take four points of damage.
Gary Young: I'll get it.
Wade Brown: Forget to rage.
Kostadis Roussos: He doesn't get to rage up until he gets to rage on his turn, not his re.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so the ogre
Kostadis Roussos: swings his axe and rolls a one.
David Mendenhall: That's a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Cuts off his own toe.
Kostadis Roussos: Bramgrim.
Gary Young: Oh.
Gary Young: I guess they would have a high strength save, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: I can walk in this dark gray.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, just every time you go on it, it counts as 10 feet of movement.
Kostadis Roussos: Going up on it costs you 10, and so you can then move normally on it.
Gary Young: So I move 20, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: And I'll just use my mace.
Kostadis Roussos: You can't.
Kostadis Roussos: Ben, you have to go back down, so you'd have to go through Bramgrim.
David Mendenhall: Missed anyway.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just saying you might want to use your spell.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what I'm trying to say.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: I will use my spell instead.
Kostadis Roussos: Or a ranged weapon.
Kostadis Roussos: That's where your choices are.
Gary Young: Well, try this new hand crossbow.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Try the new hand crossbow.
Kostadis Roussos: Gosh, darn it.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you using one of the special bullets or you're just using it for damage?
Gary Young: Roll a strength save DC 10.
David Mendenhall: You should be able to make that.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't.
David Mendenhall: What's your plus on strength size?
Kostadis Roussos: Four.
David Mendenhall: Still.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: All right.
David Mendenhall: He's prone then.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's prone.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: And he takes three damage?
Gary Young: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Did you get the damage?
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Gary Young: Forgot it.
David Mendenhall: Use a Baldur's Gate 3 standby.
Kostadis Roussos: What was that?
David Mendenhall: Make a DC3 DC13 wisdom save.
David Mendenhall: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Blows it.
David Mendenhall: He is halted and can take no actions until the end of his next turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, well, well.
David Mendenhall: Nor can he move.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Gary Young: Bramgrim.
Gary Young: All right.
Gary Young: So he is prone.
Gary Young: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: And halted.
Kostadis Roussos: So that is 12 points of damage.
Gary Young: With 14 points.
Gary Young: So 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I got that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Wade Brown: Back to top of the order is me.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let's just do you some and we'll stop after that because it's .
Wade Brown: Uh, yeah.
Wade Brown: I think I'm still best off just doing poison spray, right?
Wade Brown: Just hit it.
Wade Brown: Hit it and get out.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, boy, another four damage.
Wade Brown: Right.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: And we will stop here.
David Mendenhall: Should we just do the ogre's turn, which is to be skeptical, to do nothing, and then remove the halt condition.
Kostadis Roussos: He's still prone.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
David Mendenhall: Bramgrim starts next week.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Next week we will not be playing because I will be in Greece.
Kostadis Roussos: Probably hopelessly inebriated at this time.
Kostadis Roussos: Recovering from my inebriation.
David Mendenhall: Well, at this time in Greece, it'll be in the morning.
David Mendenhall: You're going to be drunk at in the morning?
Kostadis Roussos: Or recovering.
David Mendenhall: You're not sure which, one or the other.
Kostadis Roussos: Just a logical or here.
Wade Brown: There will be alcohol.
Wade Brown: There'll be blood in your alcohol system.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So I don't think I'll be able to be awake.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, guys.
Kostadis Roussos: Take care.
David Mendenhall: Bye-bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Bye.